<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Strategic Consulting</title>
<link>https://strategic-consult.com/news.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://strategic-consult.com/news.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.7.32</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>April / May 2025 Food Safety Insights</title>
  <dc:creator>Robert J. Ferguson</dc:creator>
  <link>https://strategic-consult.com/posts/april-may-insights.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Strategic Consulting maintains its relationship with Food Safety Magazine where we present market data and insights that we hear directly in our surveys and interviews with food safety professionals from around the world in our Food Safety Insights column. We invite anyone who wants to have a better understand the needs of food safety professionals at a ground level view to subscribe to Food Safety Magazine <a href="https://www.food-safety.com/">www.food-safety.com</a>(www.food-safety.com) and follow our Food Safety Insights columns in every issue.</p>
<section id="aprilmay-food-safety-insights" class="level2 unnumbered unlisted">
<h2 class="unnumbered unlisted anchored" data-anchor-id="aprilmay-food-safety-insights">April/May Food Safety Insights</h2>
<p>Hygienic design and sanitation are fundamentals for any food safety program. But what are the challenges and impediments to implementing and maintaining an effective program? Find out what we heard from 118 food safety professionals in 23 countries about their biggest issues with the sanitary design of the equipment, building and spaces where they work.</p>
<p>Part 1 of our 2-part series on hygienic design and sanitation is in the latest edition of Food Safety Insights in Food Safety Magazine.</p>
<p><strong>Hygienic Design: How are Processors Coping With This Essential Element of Food Safety?</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://digitaledition.food-safety.com/april-may-2025/column-food-safety-insights/?oly_enc_id=5355H1827012J4J&amp;utm_medium=brandwebsite&amp;utm_source=/eMagazine&amp;_gl=1*14hhw3r*_ga*MTI4MjYwMzI2Mi4xNzQ2Mzg1NDUx*_ga_3E07VVTPG3*czE3NTA0MjQzMTUkbzE0MCRnMCR0MTc1MDQyNDMxNiRqNTkkbDAkaDA">Food Safety Magazine April-May Food Safety Insights.</a></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://strategic-consult.com/posts/april-may-insights.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://strategic-consult.com/assets/postsAssets/aprilMay.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="148" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>June / July 2025 Food Safety Insights</title>
  <dc:creator>Robert J. Ferguson</dc:creator>
  <link>https://strategic-consult.com/posts/june-july-insights.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>The June/July Food Safety Insights in Food Safety Magazine presents Part 2 of our series on hygienic design and sanitation and what we heard from our global survey of 118 food processors in 23 countries.</p>
<p>In the good news, 81% reported having a designated “sanitarian” responsible for sanitation, but, as usual, the reality is often more complex as many report that they rely on a “team approach” while others report that their role of dedicated sanitarian has been eliminated due to resource constraints. Food safety professionals frequently have to juggle multiple responsibilities, and staff training and communication can be inconsistent, particularly when dedicated sanitarians are not maintained. Despite these challenges, most respondents give their facilities’ hygienic design and sanitation program a positive grade with 60% scoring between 6 and 9 on a 10-point scale. Find out more details in our Food Safety Insights column in the June/July issues of Food Safety Magazine</p>
<p><strong>Hygienic Design: How are Processors Coping With This Essential Element of Food Safety? — Part 2</strong> <a href="https://digitaledition.food-safety.com/june-july-2025/column-food-safety-insights/">Food Safety Magazine June-July Food Safety Insights.</a></p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://strategic-consult.com/posts/june-july-insights.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://strategic-consult.com/assets/postsAssets/juneJuly.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="147" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Regulatory Changes Are Impacting Your Food Safety Program.</title>
  <dc:creator>Robert J. Ferguson</dc:creator>
  <link>https://strategic-consult.com/posts/regulatory-changes-USDA-food-safety.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>The latest edition our Food Safety Insights column in Food Safety Magazine is now available. Find out what we heard from 150 food processors about the USDA’s new proposed Salmonella regulations in poultry, what processors wish that the USDA and other regulators understood better, and, if given the chance, what questions would you pose to USDA-FSIS leadership?</p>
<p>Read the article <a href="https://digitaledition.food-safety.com/february-march-2025/column-food-safety-insights/">here.</a></p>
<hr>
<p><em>Note:</em> Since the survey was conducted and the article published, USDA has announced that they have withdrawn the proposed salmonella regulations pending further review of the public comments received. Some of the public comments received by USDA are no doubt also reflected in the survey results and comments that we received making this survey and article nonetheless timely and insightful.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://strategic-consult.com/posts/regulatory-changes-USDA-food-safety.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://strategic-consult.com/assets/postsAssets/usda.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
